MONIKA SHARMA

Flat no 309 Jhelum Apartment plot no 8, Sec 5, Dwarka Delhi • 9718531402, 9667774685

• monikasharma2725 @gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

Seeking **Chemistry**(TGT) position with your school .

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Over 8 years' experience in teaching field. Expert in planning and implementing curriculum based on principles of science. Hands on experience in creation of engaging lessons in order to develop critical thinking skills. In depth knowledge of establishing and maintaining student behavior standards. Conversant with implementing coherent instructional plans.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Currently working with SVIS, sec-18, Dwarka as TGT Chemistry since Apr 2017 Teaching classes 9th and 10th alongwith practicals.

Worked with Maxfort school, Dwarka Delhi. Science Teacher

Nov 2014 - march 2016

- Plan and implement research based science curriculum
- Provide instruction on core sub topics such as Biology, Chemistry and Physics
- Engage students in class instruction by ensuring interesting delivery
- Monitor students' progress and ensure discipline at all times
- Ensure that all curriculum is developed based on data analysis and research
- Evaluate academic achievement and provide extra coaching to lacking students

K.C Public School Jammu

Chemistry Teacher

July 2009 - Feb 2010

- Maintained excellent classroom management skills and an ability to keep students on task
- Researched information for providing a basis for curriculum development
- Developed and reinforced school rules as instructed
- Prepared and distributed science related material to students
- Assisted in grading and checking assignments

G.D.GoenkaPublic School, Jammu

Science Teacher

March 2009 - June 2009

- Conducted morning assemblies and theme assemblies
- Prepared and implemented remedial programs for students requiring extra help
- Inspired a higher degree of parental involvement in student education

New Era Public School , Jammu

Science Teacher

Sept 2004 - May 2006

- Maintained excellent classroom management skills
- Prepared science assignments, reviewed and corrected all home works with an emphasis on providing feedback to each student .
- Utilized computer resources to give conceptual clarity to students

S Imperial AcadamySchool, Jammu

Science Teacher

May 2002 - May 2004

- Maintained excellent classroom management skills
- Prepared science assignments, reviewed and corrected all home works with an emphasis on providing feedback to each student

EDUCATIONAL INFORMATION

- Bed IGNOU 2004-06 94 %
- MCM BVIMR Pune Univ 1998-2000 with first class distinction
- BSc Chem(H) integrated Hansraj College Delhi University 1993-96

ADDITIONAL CAPABILITIES

- Results driven with a strong grasp on subject matter
- Excellent instructional and communication skills
- Profound knowledge of teaching practices and their implementation
- Analytical problem solver
- Proficient in latest teaching technologies

Personal Profile

- D.O.B 27th July 1976
- Husband's Name : Mr. Ajay Sharma
- Nationality : Indian